(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
NAKIRI AYAME BIRTHDAY Anniversary Live
誇り高きアイドル
作詞：shito,Gom 作曲：shito
Proud Idol
Lyrics: shito, Gom / Composition: shito
私のこと知ってますか？
Do you know about me?
可愛く見えてますか？
Do I look cute to you?
私の歌どうだろうな
I wonder how my singing is.
うまく歌えてますか？
Am I singing it well?
衣装だとかメイクだとか
The outfit, the makeup...
可愛く見えてますか？
...do I look cute to you?
振り付けとかファンサだとか
The choreography, the fan service...
喜んでもらえますか？
...do you enjoy them?
手は冷たくなって
My hands are getting cold...
足は震える
...and my legs are trembling.
それでも戦いたい
Even so, I want to fight.
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol.
バカにする奴は嫌いだ
I hate those who make fun of us.
見下されるのも嫌いだ
I hate being looked down upon too.
アイドルなんかって言葉を
Words like "it's just an idol"...
見てもいないくせに言うな
...don't say them if you haven't even looked.
頑張りも当然と言うな
Don't say hard work is a given.
イメージとか強制するな
Don't force your image on me.
アイドルなんかって言葉を
The phrase "it's just an idol"...
この世で一番大嫌いだ
...I hate it more than anything in this world.
プライベート見えないから
Since you can't see my private life,
分からないと思います
I don't think you'd understand.
性格とか悪い方です
My personality is on the bad side.
騙しちゃっていますか？
Am I deceiving you?
でも本気です 本気なんです
But I'm serious, I'm really serious.
ありのままの私を
Please like me just as I am,
好きになって推してください
and support me.
それってワガママですか？
Is that being selfish?
きっと可愛くない
I'm sure it's not cute,
ぜんぶわかってる
I understand everything.
それでも好かれていたい
Even so, I want to be liked.
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol.
皮肉言う奴は嫌いだ
I hate those who are cynical.
言い訳ばかりも嫌いだ
I also hate making excuses.
こんなもんかって言葉を
Words like "is this it?"...
軽々しく口にするな
...don't say them so lightly.
勝手に限界決めるな
Don't decide my limits for me.
笑いものになんてするな
Don't make me a laughingstock.
アイドルなんかって言葉を
The phrase "it's just an idol"...
この世で一番大嫌いだ
...I hate it more than anything in this world.
向かい風を切り裂け
Cut through the headwind.
誇り高きアイドル
A proud idol.
目指そうぜ
Let's aim for it.
応援がなければ活動できない
I can't do this without your support.
好きなことばかりじゃ生きてはいけない
I can't live just by doing what I like.
元気あげるはずが もらってばかりだし
I'm supposed to give energy, but I'm always receiving it.
恩返しできる日まで
Until the day I can repay you,
待ってて
please wait.
完璧だと思っても
Even if I think it's perfect,
飽きられちゃっても
or if people get tired of me,
それでも笑っていたい
Even so, I want to keep smiling.
アイドルだから
Because I'm an idol.
...愛があって
...with love,
スタッフさんの愛があって
with the staff's love,
いつも家族の愛があって
with my family's love always,
生きてる
I live as an
アイドル
idol.
馬鹿にする奴は嫌いだ
I hate those who make fun of us.
見下されるのも嫌いだ
I hate being looked down upon too.
アイドルなんかという言葉を
Don't say things like "just an idol"
見てもいないくせに言うな
when you haven't even seen us.
頑張りは当然と言うな
Don't say hard work is to be expected.
イメージとか強要するな
Don't force images on us.
アイドルなんかという言葉は
The words "just an idol" are
この世で一番大嫌いな
what I hate most in this world...
君にBaby Sweet Berry Love
To you, Baby Sweet Berry Love.
Baby Sweet Berry Love
作詞：山崎寛子 作曲・編曲：俊龍
Lyrics: Hiroko Yamazaki, Composition/Arrangement: Shunryu
本当の気持ちだけ
If only we could
分け合えたらいいのにな
share our true feelings.
願いを叶えてよ
Please grant my wish.
大好きのハートも
Even the "I love you" hearts,
ごめんねの涙も
even the "I'm sorry" tears,
本当は素直に
I actually wanted to
見せたくて
show them honestly.
伝えたい思いと
The feelings I want to convey
裏腹の態度
and my contradictory attitude.
上手になれない
A state of mind
心模様
that I can't get right.
どうして 空回りに
Why does my heart
胸がギュッとなる
tighten in vain?
近い距離がもどかしいよね
This close distance is frustrating, isn't it?
届けたいの
I want to reach you.
君とBaby Sweet Berry Love
With you, Baby Sweet Berry Love.
きっとぎこちなくて
It's a bit awkward,
でもまっすぐに見つめて
but look straight at me.
素顔写したい
I want to show my true face.
もっとBaby Sweet Berry Love
More Baby Sweet Berry Love.
せめて君の前では
At least in front of you,
笑っておこうぜ溢れた
let's keep smiling, it's overflowing.
ありのままでいたい
I want to stay as I am.
だからBaby Sweet Berry Love
So Baby Sweet Berry Love,
一緒に始めよう
let's start together.
散らばれたハートを
I try to look for
探してみるけれど
the scattered hearts,
本当は自分の
but they're actually
奥にある
deep inside myself.
まるで寂しいのに
Like a lost cat
すました迷い猫
acting cool despite being lonely.
こぼれた夕日に
I get emotional
ジーンとしちゃう
at the spilling sunset.
不意な優しさに
The sound of my heart
はしゃぐ胸の音
frolicking at unexpected kindness.
ドタバタとかカラフルでキュンと
It's noisy and colorful and my heart throbs,
満ちてゆくの
and it fills up.
君とBaby Sweet Berry Love
With you, Baby Sweet Berry Love.
感情のままだけ
The more I cherish just
大事にすればするほど
the emotions as they are,
ごまかしてしまうの
the more I end up hiding them.
だけどBaby Sweet Berry Love
But Baby Sweet Berry Love,
自分の心まで
when I don't even know
分からない時は君と
my own heart, I want to
確かめ合いたいの
confirm it with you.
だからBaby Sweet Berry Love
So Baby Sweet Berry Love,
同じ場所にいたい
I want to be in the same place.
君にBaby Sweet Berry Love
To you, Baby Sweet Berry Love.
自分を守るより
There's something more important
大切なことがあるの
than protecting myself,
こんなに近くに
right here so close.
君とBaby Sweet Berry Love
With you, Baby Sweet Berry Love.
きっとぎこちなくて
It's a bit awkward,
でもまっすぐに見つめて
but look straight at me.
素顔写したい
I want to show my true face.
もっとBaby Sweet Berry Love
More Baby Sweet Berry Love.
せめて君の前では
At least in front of you,
笑っておこうぜ溢れた
let's keep smiling, it's overflowing.
ありのままでいたい
I want to stay as I am.
だからBaby Sweet Berry Love
So Baby Sweet Berry Love,
こんなに好きだよ
I love you this much.
ずっとBaby Sweet Berry Love
Always Baby Sweet Berry Love.
伝え合った 心の温度を
The warmth of our hearts we shared,
そっと 大事そうに 抱え歩いていた
I walked, gently clutching it as if it were precious
答えのない 願いの中で
Within a wish that has no answer,
言葉は 未来 変えて
words change the future
幼い頃 ずっと 夢に見ていた
Something I’d dreamed of since I was a child
私には まだ 遠いけど
It’s still out of reach for me, but...
君がいれば
...if you are here,
少しは強くなれる気がして
I feel like I can become a little stronger
明日の色を重ねる歌
A song that layers the colors of tomorrow
呼んだ希望辿って 止めた世界を超えた
Following the hope I called for, I surpassed the frozen world
諦めない想い いつしか心繋げた
Feelings that won't give up eventually connected our hearts
泣いていたって笑って 明日迎えに行こう
Even if we were crying, let's smile and go greet tomorrow
決めた誓い辛くて 倒れても
Even if the oath I made is painful and I fall...
君のココロを守るため
...it's all to protect your heart
記憶のない 時の流れに
In the flow of time where memories are absent,
きっと 求めていた 暖かさはあって
the warmth I was seeking must surely be there
包まれた 瞬間すべての
At the moment I was enveloped, all my...
想いは 君へ巡る
...feelings came circling back to you
空に向かって 走り手にした
I ran toward the sky and grasped
幾つもの 尊い光 胸にしまって
many precious lights, tucking them into my chest
私の中の 輝きに変え
Turning them into a radiance within me,
迷いを 全部払って飛ぼう
I'll cast away all hesitation and fly
正解の見えない 入り組んだ迷路を抜け
Escaping the intricate maze where the right answer is hidden
君が流した涙で 心目覚めた
My heart was awakened by the tears you shed
そして知った世界は こんなにもまだ綺麗で
And the world I came to know is still so beautiful
新しい可能性を 生むだろう
It will surely give birth to new possibilities
時のカケラの 願いから
From a wish born of a fragment of time
救い信じて 溢れた想い
Believing in salvation, these overflowing feelings
確かな 始まりに立って
Stand at a certain beginning
君の笑顔 取り戻すよ
I will take back your smile,
真実の 奇跡になって
becoming a true miracle
呼んだ希望辿って 止めた世界を超えた
Following the hope I called for, I surpassed the frozen world
諦めない想い いつしか心繋げた
Feelings that won't give up eventually connected our hearts
泣いていたって笑って 明日迎えに行こう
Even if we were crying, let's smile and go greet tomorrow
決めた誓い辛くて 倒れても
Even if the oath I made is painful and I fall...
君のココロを守るため
...it's all to protect your heart
君の
To your...
そばにいよう
...side, I will stay
いつの間にか見つけてた 遠い夢
A distant dream I found before I knew it
一人じゃ見えなかった景色
A scenery I couldn't have seen alone
波打つ風の音 加速していく想いに
To the sound of the surging wind and accelerating feelings,
戸惑いを覚えた
I felt a sense of bewilderment
ずっと追いかけた 理想の姿は
The ideal self I've always chased
まだ届かなくて 遠いけど
is still out of reach and far away, but...
きっとこの瞬間を かけがえないみんなで
Surely, this moment, with everyone who is irreplaceable...
共に行こう
...let's go together
手を繋いで 3, 2, 1
Hands held together, 3, 2, 1
輝き宿して
With a glow dwelling within
夢の場所へ 駆け抜けていく
We'll run through to the place of our dreams
僕たちの青春の光は
The light of our youth
誰にも止められないよ
Cannot be stopped by anyone
笑い合う分だけ 優しく
As much as we laugh together, gently
こぼれる涙さえ
Even the falling tears
ほら 輝かせ
Look, I'll make them shine
明日へ運ぶから
And carry them to tomorrow
君の隣へ
To your side
僕たちは世界を超えていく
We will cross over the world
迎えに行くよ
I'm coming to get you
まだ見えない明日も
Even the yet unseen tomorrow
キラめきに変えてきっと
I'll surely turn it into a sparkle
僕たちが 未来へと
Because we toward the future
連れて行くから！
Will take you there!
背伸びして手を伸ばす 憧れの
Stretching out my hand to reach my aspiration
行先示す星になろう
I'll become the star that shows the way
躓くその度に 手を差し伸べ合えたら
If we can lend a hand every time we stumble
すぐに届くはずさ
It should reach us soon
そっと踏み出した 小さな勇気が
The small courage I softly stepped out with
もう 消えないように 繋げよう
Let's connect it so it never fades away
不安も愛しさも 大切に抱きしめて
Embracing both anxiety and love dearly
共にいくよ
Let's go together
目を合わせて 3, 2, 1
Eyes meeting, 3, 2, 1
晴れ渡る希望へ
Toward a clear, bright hope
飛び出せるよ 突き抜けていく
We can leap out, we'll break through
僕たちの透き通る決意は
Our transparent determination
まだまだ止められないよ
Still cannot be stopped
ありきたりな今日こそ
Precisely because it's an ordinary today
ドキドキに変えてもっと
Let's turn it into more excitement
僕たちが いつまでも
Because we will always
背中を押すから！
Push you from behind!
ずっと一人で描いてた キャンバス
The canvas I've been drawing on alone all this time
いつからか 色彩(ライト)になって
At some point, it became colors of light
また少しずつ 芽生えた
Again, little by little, what blossomed
「大好き」を紡ぎ
Spinning these 'loves' together
どこまでも高く
Soaring ever higher
あすいろの空へ 駆け抜けていく
Toward the azure sky, we'll run through
僕たちの青春の光は
The light of our youth
誰にも止められないよ
Cannot be stopped by anyone
笑い合う分だけ 優しく
As much as we laugh together, gently
こぼれる涙さえ
Even the falling tears
ほら 輝かせ
Look, I'll make them shine
明日へ運ぶから
And carry them to tomorrow
君の隣へ
To your side
僕たちは世界を超えていく
We will cross over the world
迎えに行くよ
I'm coming to get you
まだ見えない明日も
Even the yet unseen tomorrow
キラめきに変えてきっと
I'll surely turn it into a sparkle
僕たちが 未来へと
Because we toward the future
果てのない 未来へと
Toward an endless future
連れて行くから！
Will take you there!
おめでとー！
Congratulations!
わぁーい！
Yay!
あやめ、あやめー！
Ayame, Ayame!
おめでとー！
Congratulations!
お誕生日おめでとー！
Happy Birthday!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
おめでとうございまーす！
Congratulations!
嬉しい、ありがとう！
I'm so happy, thank you!
よしよしよし...
There, there, there...
幸せ...
I'm so happy...
ありがとね、二人とも集まってくれて、ありがとうございます。
Thank you both for gathering here, thank you so much.
いやいやいや...
No, no, no...
本当にね。
Really.
可愛いねぇ。
So cute.
幸せ...
So happy...
よしよしよしよしよし...
There, there, there, there...
幸せ...
So happy...
というわけで今回は、あすいろClearSkyだったんだ。
So this time, it was Asuiro Clear Sky.
え、なんかさ、
Well, you see,
ちょっと、君たちさ、
Listen, you guys,
お？
Oh?
だいぶ「百花繚乱花吹雪」をやってきたじゃない？
We've done 'Hyakka Ryouran Hanafubuki' quite a lot, right?
やりましたー！踊りまくりました！
We did! We danced like crazy!
踊りまくりましたよねー。
We really did, didn't we?
そうですね。
That's true.
だったので、ちょっと、新しい歌を3人で歌ったことない、
So, I thought I'd like for the three of us
3人でね、歌いたいなと思って、
To sing a new song we haven't done together before.
おおー！なるほどねー！
Oh! I see!
で、ちょっとお家でね、あすいろClearSkyを聴いていた時に、
And when I was listening to Asuiro Clear Sky at home,
ほう。
Hmm.
「あれ？」
'Wait a minute?'
お？
Oh?
「百花繚乱チームで歌ったら...」
'If the Hyakka Ryouran team sang this...'
お？
Oh?
「エモいんじゃねーか？」と思って！
'Wouldn't it be really touching?' I thought!
おおー、エモい！エモいよ！
Oh, it is! It's so touching!
あとさ、声のバランスがすごい3人は...
Also, the vocal balance between the three of us...
いい感じにね、合わさるので、
They go together nicely, so...
おお〜
Ooh~
とても良いのではないのでしょうか、と思って選びました。
I thought it would be very good, so I chose it.
イエーイ！
Yay!
わざわざありがとうございます。歌ってくれて。
Thank you for taking the time to sing with me.
いやいや。ありがとう。
No, no. Thank you.
ありがとうね。誘ってくれて。
Thank you. For inviting us.
誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
またなんかね、こんな感じのまた後でわちゃわちゃ...
Maybe we can have another chaotic time like this later...
そうだね。3人で。
Right. The three of us.
どこに...
Where...
なんか、え？3人いる、え？
Wait, huh? There are three of us? Huh?
なんかね、百花繚乱みたいなね。
Like "Hyakkaryouran," you know?
なんかね、覚えがあるよね。
Yeah, it feels familiar.
こういう...
This kind of...
こういう踊り、あれ？あれれ？
This dance... wait? Huh?
あれ？なんか...
Wait? Something...
なんか、またあったらいいよね。
It would be nice to do it again.
またあったらね。
If we can.
体が勝手に...
My body's moving on its own...
あれ？あれ？
Wait? Huh?
踊り始めちゃう。あれ？あれ？
I'm starting to dance. Wait? Huh?
(笑い声)
(Laughter)
何かしらで、また3人でね、楽曲がまた出せたら...
Hopefully we can release another song together again...
いいですね。
That would be nice.
まぁ、乞うご期待ということで。
Well, please look forward to it.
ということで。
And with that...
皆さん、お楽しみくださいませ。
Everyone, please enjoy.
お楽しみくださいませ。
Please enjoy.
お楽しみにだの！
Look forward to it!
お楽しみにしてください。
Please look forward to it.
日本語難しい！
Japanese is hard!
難しいね。
It's hard.
さぁ、我々と、あやめ殿とね。
Now, we and Ayame-dono...
おん。
Yeah.
フブちゃんも、おん。この後も見届けようじゃないか。
Fubuchan too, yeah. Let's watch this through to the end.
じゃあ、ちょっとステージのね...
Well, we'll go over to...
その辺にちょっと...
Somewhere around there...
サイリウムを持って行きたいと思います！
And bring our penlights!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
頑張ってね！バイバイ！
Good luck! Bye-bye!
バイバイ！頑張ります！
Bye-bye! I'll do my best!
仮面越し 今日も見えている
I can see even through the mask today
いつもと変わりない笑顔
The same smile as always
纏う それは仮面か
Is that which you wear a mask?
本当の自分を教えて
Tell me your true self
着飾り澄ました顔じゃなく
Not your dressed-up, composed face
呆れるほど 臆病な
So cowardly it's appalling
偽りは it's all nothing
Falsehoods, it's all nothing
it's all nothing
真実は open my heart
The truth, open my heart
open my heart
君に 全てを 受け止めてほしい
I want you to accept everything
加速していく世界で
In this accelerating world
生きていく僕ら
Living on, we
聞き飽きたよ 比べたがりの声
I'm tired of hearing voices that want to compare
1か0かで
By 1 or 0
決められた
Decided
運命ならば
If it is fate
抗うよ 見つけるよ
I will resist, I will find
僕である理由
The reason for being me
カワイイだけじゃもういられない
I can't just be "cute" anymore
声をあげていくんだ
I'm going to raise my voice
スターダストソング
Stardust Song
憧れの自分へ 目一杯
To my idealized self, with all my might
足元見るだけで 精一杯
Just looking at my feet is all I can do
案じているような僕には
To me who seems to be worrying
君に触れることはできるのか
Can I even reach you?
Please me answer
Please answer me
鑑定不能な myself
Inestimable myself
君と 灯す 心のまま
Just as my heart glows with you
飛び出せ！
Leap out!
加速していく世界で
In this accelerating world
生きていく僕ら
Living on, we
未知の方へ 歩むことはやめない
We won't stop walking toward the unknown
1か8かの
An all or nothing
賭けだとしても構わない
Gamble, I don't care if it is
立ち向かい 戦うよ
I will stand up and fight
頂点を目指す
Aiming for the top
そのために
For that purpose
それは 全力のなかに
That is within one's best effort
声は 力に 変わる
Voices turn into power
Up for star もう迷うことはない
Up for star, there's no more hesitation
僕だけの
Only mine
道しるべ
Signpost
胸に刻んで
Carved into my chest
加速していく世界で
In this accelerating world
生きていく僕ら
Living on, we
聞き飽きたよ 比べたがりの声
I'm tired of hearing voices that want to compare
1か0かで
By 1 or 0
決められた運命ならば
If it is a predetermined fate
抗うよ 見つけるよ
I will resist, I will find
僕である理由
The reason for being me
いつまでも 僕らしくありたい
I want to be myself forever
今も輝くんだスターダストソング
Even now, it shines, Stardust Song
カワイイだけじゃもういられない
I can't just be cute anymore
声をあげていくんだスターダストソング
I'll raise my voice, Stardust Song
はい！はい！いかがでしたでしょうか
Yes! Yes! How was it?
なんかちょっと可愛い可愛い
It was kinda cute, cute
そんな盛り方するの？
You're hyping it up like that?
ねえ、あやめちゃんのこと好きってよ！
Hey, I'm saying I like Ayame-chan!
あ、すみませんすみませんということで、ありがとうございます
Ah, excuse me, excuse me, so, thank you very much
今日はね、いやありがとうございました。すいちゃんとトワちゃんに来ていただけました！
Today, well, thank you so much. Suisei-chan and Towa-chan could come!
来ましたー！わー！
We came! Yay!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
ありがとう！ありがとうございます！
Thank you! Thank you very much!
今日はですね、あの最近ヨガずっと
Today, well, recently I've been doing yoga...
トワちゃんとすいちゃんとおかゆでスターダストソング踊ってたやつをね
The one where Towa-chan, Suisei-chan, and Okayu were dancing to Stardust Song...
はい、はいはい
Yes, yes yes
一生聴いてて
I've been listening to it non-stop
めっちゃかっこいいと思って、おかゆはちょっと別の曲で歌ってもらおうと思って
Thinking it's so cool, I thought I'd have Okayu sing a different song
はい
Yes
この二人とね、乗っかってスターダストソング一緒に踊りたい、歌いたいと思って
I thought I wanted to join these two and dance and sing Stardust Song together
やったー！
Yay!
呼んでもらった！
We were invited!
今日来ていただきました！
They came today!
やったー！
Yay!
いやでも本当に、あやめちゃんから声かけてもらえるとは思わなくて
No, but seriously, I didn't think I'd get a call from Ayame-chan
思わなくて！
Didn't think so!
トワさん？
Towa-san?
トワさん？同じこと思った
Towa-san? I thought the same thing
あやめちゃんが誘ってくれると思ってなくて
I didn't expect Ayame-chan to invite me
え、うそー！
Eh, no way!
今日はね、心臓バクバクだったの。だって初めてじゃん
Today, my heart was pounding. Because it's the first time, right?
あ、そうそう
Ah, right, right
すいちゃんとはマジで初めて、こう3Dライブでね
With Suisei-chan, it's really the first time in a 3D live like this
そうそうそう
Right, right, right
一緒にこう3人でやるみたいな
Doing it together as three like this
そうそうないない
Yeah, there hasn't been
トワちゃんは、あの、何だっけ、丸山？
Towa-chan, well, what was it, Maruyama?
丸山、うん
Maruyama, yeah
あったけど、でもこうやって歌うのは初めてじゃない？
We had that, but it's the first time singing like this, right?
ねえ、めっちゃ緊張したの。誘って大丈夫？って
Hey, I was so nervous. Like, 'is it okay to invite them?'
ありがとう、あやめちゃんみたいなレアキャラに
Thank you, to a rare character like Ayame-chan
ねえ、レアキャラにね
Yeah, a rare character
やめてよ！えー、いいじゃん可愛い
Stop it! Eh, it's fine, you're cute
どうしたの
What's wrong?
うわー
Uwaa
うわーって何
What do you mean 'Uwaa'?
え、違うの。もうなんか、本当は断られるかもってちょっとめちゃ胃がキリキリしながら言ったの
Eh, no. I was like, actually, they might refuse, so my stomach was churning while I said it
いやいやいや
No, no, no
ちょっと悩んだけどね
I hesitated a bit, though
悩んだ？
You hesitated?
いやー！って言ったでしょ
I said 'No way!', didn't I?
いやいやいや、もう普通に、でもめっちゃ早くなかった？返事
No, no, it was normal, but wasn't the reply super fast?
乗る！って
I'm in!
二人ともね、めっちゃ早かったの
Both of them were super fast
ほら！
See!
トワちゃん何か2日3日ぐらい寝かされるかなと思ったんだけど
I thought Towa-chan might let it sit for 2 or 3 days
いやもう即答だった、朝起きて、お、あやめちゃんから来てると思って
No, it was an instant reply, I woke up in the morning and saw 'Oh, it's from Ayame-chan'
そうそう、即答で「いいよ」って言ってくれて
Right, right, she replied instantly saying 'Okay'
感動したの
I was moved
ほらやりたがってるでしょ
See, they wanted to do it
冗談冗談
Just kidding, just kidding
ということでですね、本日はありがとうございました
So, thank you very much for today
あ、こちらこそありがとうございました
Ah, thank you as well
お時間みたいなんで
Looks like our time is up
はい、すいちゃんこの辺で帰るか
Yes, Suisei-chan, shall we head out?
はい、失礼いたします
Yes, excuse us
じゃあね、さよなら、バイバイ、頑張って！
See ya, goodbye, bye-bye, good luck!
こんな終わり方すんの？頑張れ！
It ends like this? Good luck!
いやめっちゃ雑なんだけど。大丈夫かな
Wow, that was so blunt. I wonder if it's okay
夢見る空へ
作詞：永塚健登 作曲：永塚健登
To the Dreaming Sky
Lyrics: Kento Nagatsuka, Composition: Kento Nagatsuka
重ねた手はギュッと離さずに
Holding our joined hands tightly without letting go
行くよ 行こう 夢見る空へ
Let's go, let's go, to the dreaming sky
窓越しに見上げた
Looking up through the window
とても小さな空
At a very small sky
ここで出会えたのは
That we met here
数え切れない奇跡
Is a countless miracle
繰り返した一歩が
Each repeated step
煌めきを繋いで
Connects the sparkles
星のような笑顔 導いた
A smile like a star guided us
Day by Day
みんなの声が力になる
Everyone's voice becomes our strength
Stage by Stage
ここでそれぞれ目指すもの
What each of us aims for here
それぞれ描くもの
What each of us draws
それぞれ願った夢へ
To the dreams we each wished for
重ねた手はギュッと離さずに
Holding our joined hands tightly without letting go
ひとりひとり違う色で
Each one with a different color
咲き誇るトキメキ
A throb of excitement in full bloom
振り向くことなくまっすぐに
Straight ahead without looking back
行くよ 行こう 夢見る空へ
Let's go, let's go, to the dreaming sky
夢見る空へ
To the Dreaming Sky
笑い合ったことや
The things we laughed about
尽きそうにない話題
and the topics that never seemed to end,
思い出いっぱいなのに
even though they're full of memories,
あっという間の日々
the days went by in a flash.
上書きじゃなくて
Not overwriting them,
名前付けて保存
but saving them with names.
どれも全部大切に生きてゆける
I can live while cherishing every single one of them.
One for All
みんなのための力になる
Becoming a strength for everyone.
All for One
今日も賑やかすぎるくらい
It's almost too lively again today.
笑顔が止まらない
The smiles just won't stop.
思いは膨らんでゆく
The feelings keep growing.
重ねた今 ギュッと噛み締めた
I savored this moment we've layered together.
ひとりひとり違う声で
Each and every person with a different voice,
歌声が広がる
The singing voices spread out.
風を感じたら まっすぐに行くよ
Once I feel the breeze, I'll go straight ahead.
行こう 夢見る空へ
Let's go towards the dreaming sky.
憧れて 手を伸ばし
Yearning for it, reaching out my hand,
掴みとった その光が
that light I finally grasped...
いつの日か また誰かの
will one day, for someone else again,
憧れに変わる
turn into a yearning.
繋げよう
Let's pass it on.
重ねた手は ギュッと離さずに
Holding our joined hands tightly, without letting go,
ひとりひとり違う色で 描き出すトキメキ
Each and every person with a different color, painting this excitement.
出会えた全てに ありがとう
Thank you for everything I've encountered.
奇跡だって 起こし続け ずっと ずっと そばにいるよ
I'll keep making miracles happen, and stay by your side forever and ever.
行こう 夢見る空へ
Let's go towards the dreaming sky.
あやめ先輩！
Ayame-senpai!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy Birthday to you!
ありがとうございまーす！
Thank you very much!
あやめ先輩 何歳になったんですか？
Ayame-senpai, how old are you now?
余は、えーっと、1500...4、5歳ぐらいになりました！
I've turned, uh, around 1500... 4 or 5 years old!
おばあ...
Grandma...
ギスギスしないの！
Don't be mean!
いやでもダンス頑張ったね。
But you really worked hard on the dance.
ねえ。みんなで揃えてね。こうやって「夢見る空へ」って。
Right. We all aligned, didn't we? Doing "Yumemiru Sora e" like this.
なんかこれ、あれなんだよね。マリンと余はBloomで。
This was, you know... Marine and I were in Bloom.
そうそう。Bloom。踊ってました、見てました。
Right, right. Bloom. We danced it, we saw it.
団長だけやったことなくて、ちょっと、んー、心配だったんだけど。
Only Danchou hadn't done it before, so I was a bit... hmmm, worried.
なんと！今回この二人が先生になってくれて、教えてくれたんですよ。
But wait! These two became my teachers this time and taught me.
はい、うぃんうぃんいきますよ！
Yes, win-win, here we go!
はい！高速ステップいきますよ！
Yes! Fast steps, here we go!
ちなみにここ3回ぐらい間違えました。
By the way, I messed up here about 3 times.
間違えましたね。でも何度も撮り直しましたけど。無事に形になりました！
You did. But we re-shot it many times. And it safely took shape!
よかったし、あとここがピタッと。きれいだったよね、最後。
It was good, and also this part was perfectly in sync. It was beautiful, right? The end.
ねえ。どうでしたか皆さん？
Yeah. How was it, everyone?
いっぱいスクショして、ハッシュタグで呟くんだぞ、お前ら！
Take lots of screenshots and tweet them with the hashtag, you lot!
いやー。そう、あやめ先輩誕生日ということで。
Wow. So, since it's Ayame-senpai's birthday...
ちょっと誕生日プレゼントじゃないんですけど。
It's not exactly a birthday present, but...
団長やっぱあやめ先輩、今回こうダンスとか教えてくれたりとか、あとお呼ばれしてくださったんで。
Since Ayame-senpai taught me the dance and invited me here...
え、ちなみに、あやめ先輩、サンタさんは信じてますか？
By the way, Ayame-senpai, do you believe in Santa Claus?
そりゃサンタさんいるよ！
Of course there's a Santa Claus!
そうですよね。団長、あやめ先輩のために。
I thought so. Danchou has, for Ayame-senpai...
なんと、サンタさんを呼んできました！
Guess what, I've brought Santa Claus!
ホッホッホ。メリークリスマス！
Ho ho ho. Merry Christmas!
あやめちゃん、メリークリスマス。サンタさんじゃよ。ホッホッホ。
Ayame-chan, Merry Christmas. It's Santa Claus. Ho ho ho.
誰だ？
Who's that?
サンタさん、サンタさんです。
It's Santa, Santa Claus.
あやめちゃん、サンタじゃよ。よしよし、いい子いい子。
Ayame-chan, it's Santa. There, there, good girl, good girl.
怖い、怖い、やだー！
Scary, scary, nooo!
We wish you a Merry Christmas... (Singing)
adrenaline!!!
単純な言葉 重ねてゆく
Simple words keep piling up
もっと心は素直で
Let my heart be more honest
なんでもないようなその笑顔が
That casual smile of yours
明日を照らす光に
Will be the light that shines on tomorrow
ずっと気付いていたんだって
I've always known that
この手に抱えていたんだって
I was holding it in these hands
弾けた声に 流した答えが
In the popping voice, the answer I let out
今 そっと きっと 願い込めた
Now, softly, surely, I've put my wish into it
ずっとまわる まわる 夢の中で
Always turning, turning in a dream
繰り返し君と踊った
I danced with you over and over
揺れる景色 道は続く
The swaying scenery, the road continues
通り過ぎる風に吹かれ
Blown by the passing wind
何度も越えて行けるから 境界線
I can cross it over and over, the boundary line
雲かき分けて手を伸ばした
I pushed through the clouds and reached out my hand
涙は今浮かぶ空に
Tears are now in the floating sky
預けて走り出すの
I'll leave them behind and start running
並んで見つけた
We found it standing side by side
輝く光を手に
The shining light in our hands
問題はいつも自分次第
Problems are always up to yourself
さあ未来を選んで
Come on, choose your future
こんがらがっていた紐解いた
I unraveled what was tangled
思いのまま進もう
Let's move forward as we wish
毎日冒険なんだって
Every day is an adventure
奇跡は無限大なんだって
Miracles are infinite
高鳴る思い 羅針盤のように
My throbbing feelings are like a compass
今 そっと きっと 導いてく
Now, softly, surely, they'll guide me
そうだ巡る 巡る 波に乗っかって
That's right, going around, riding the waves
風まかせ君と笑った
Laughing with you, letting the wind take us
予想外は 想定内
The unexpected is within expectations
間違いや失敗も楽しんで
Enjoy the mistakes and failures too
一歩踏み出したら見えた可能性
Possibilities appeared when I took a step forward
行き止まりの壁壊して
Break down the walls of dead ends
まだ知らない 世界君と
An unknown world, with you
一緒なら怖くないよ
I won't be afraid if we're together
わくわくしている
I'm so excited
今が一番大好き
I love the present most of all
ゆっくり ゆっくり 焦らず 焦らず
Slowly, slowly, don't rush, don't rush
自分の 自分の 歩幅で行こう
Let's go at our own pace
大丈夫 大丈夫 心配ない 心配ない
It's okay, it's okay, no worries, no worries
描いたもの 全部叶えるよ
I'll make everything I pictured come true
ずっとまわる まわる 夢の中で
Always turning, turning in a dream
繰り返し君と踊った
I danced with you over and over
いつか君と 約束した
That promise I made with you one day
願いの架け橋を渡って
I'll cross the bridge of wishes
何度も越えて行けるから 境界線
I can cross it over and over, the boundary line
雲かき分けて手を伸ばした
I pushed through the clouds and reached out my hand
涙は今 浮かぶ空に
Tears are now in the floating sky
預けて走り出すよ
I'll leave them behind and start running
並んで見つけた
We found it standing side by side
輝く光を手に
The shining light in our hands
わくわくしている
I'm so excited
今が一番大好き
I love the present most of all
あやめちゃん！
Ayame-chan!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ねぇ前回もね、来てくれたのに
You know, even though you came last time,
今回も来てくれてありがとうございます。
thank you for coming this time as well.
はーい、呼んでくれてめっちゃ嬉しいよ。
Of course! I'm so happy you invited me.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
なんかね、前回はさ、なんかこう
Well, last time,
余がおかゆんと、で、余がころねんと、って
I danced with Okayu-n, and then with Korone-n,
それぞれで踊ったんだけど、
separately, but...
今回はおかころの二人と一緒に
this time I wanted to sing and dance together
歌って踊りたかったんよね。
with the OkaKoro duo.
ほうほうほう。
I see, I see.
で、何歌おうかなって考えた時に...
So, when I was thinking about what to sing...
おかころに歌ってほしい曲をね、あの、ベースに考えていたんですけど。
I was thinking of a song I wanted OkaKoro to sing as the base.
あ、そうなの？
Oh, really?
そうなの？
Is that so?
アドレナリンを聴いた時に、この二人のてぇてぇ感じに歌ってほしいと思ってね。
When I heard 'Adrenaline!!!', I thought I wanted you two to sing it in a wholesome way.
で、そこに、あわよくば余もちょっと添えられたらな、みたいな。
And I thought, if possible, I could be added to that too.
いやいや、主役だから！
No, no, you're the star!
そうだよ。
That's right.
あくまでお二人を基準に選んだ曲なんですけれども。
It's a song I chose based strictly on you two.
えー、そうなのー。
Eh, is that so?
うれしいねぇ。一生懸命みんなわちゃわちゃ踊ってくれた。
That's happy. Everyone worked hard dancing together.
いやいや、とんでもない。
No, not at all.
えー、すごい。でもこの三人よかったよね。
Wow, great. But this trio was good, wasn't it?
ねー。なんだかんだ、初めてじゃない？
Yeah. Come to think of it, isn't this the first time?
初めて。そう、めちゃレアなんだよ。
The first time. Yes, it's very rare.
レアなんだよね。
It's rare.
レア。めちゃてぇてぇだった。
Rare. It was so wholesome.
てぇてぇだった。
It was wholesome.
てぇてぇてぇだったよね。
It was triple wholesome.
てぇてぇてぇ。
Triple wholesome.
三人だから。
Because there's three of us.
あ、てぇてぇてぇね。
Ah, triple wholesome.
てぇてぇてぇだったね。
It was triple wholesome.
てぇてぇてぇだった。
まあそうだね、もう今夜限りでしょうね、この組み合わせも。
Well, that's right. This combination might be for tonight only.
今夜限りなの？
Tonight only?
え、今日で終わりですか？
Eh, is it over today?
まあ、今日限りでしょ。レアだから。
Well, it's today only. Because it's rare.
なるほどね。
I see.
今夜限りだからこその良さがあるってことか。
So there's a merit specifically because it's for tonight only.
そうなの、そうなの。
That's right, that's right.
これからは、ない…
So from now on, there won't...
ない？
Be any more?
ないってことだね。
Be any more, right?
あらー…。
Oh dear...
（泣き声）
(Crying sounds)
あやめ様、大丈夫？
Lady Ayame, are you okay?
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
どうしよう。
What should I do?
（泣き声）
(Crying sounds)
まあ、そうだね、そっとしておいてあげようね。
Well, let's just leave her alone for now.
clever
作詞：渡辺翔 作曲：渡辺翔
Lyrics: Sho Watanabe, Composition: Sho Watanabe
あぁ　流れ着いてついたって　何も
Ah, even if I drifted and arrived here, I feel nothing
感じない　せめて誰かここに　綴って
At least let someone write something here
ねぇ　決められたコースに　ハマって
Hey, getting stuck in a predetermined course
しかたない
I can't help it
今の意味を見ずに行くの
Going on without looking at the meaning of now
退屈な色を　溶かして　ちょっとでも
Dissolve the boring colors, even if just a little
和えろ　建前を　作って　守って
Mix them together, creating and protecting the facade
このゲームみたいな箱の中
Inside this box that's like a game
泳いで　足掻いて　居場所探した
Swimming, struggling, searching for a place to belong
ほら　混ざり合い不揃いな　葛藤の中　歌って
Look, singing amidst the messy, mismatched conflicts
真実も現実も　重ねて　見失ってた
Truth and reality overlapped, and I lost sight of them
まなざしが胸に起き　唯一残った条件持って
A gaze awakens in my heart, holding the only remaining condition
世界に寄り添っていこう
Let's get close to the world
世界は一つでもないし
The world is not just one
あぁ　常識に飲まれた　出口と
Ah, the exit swallowed by common sense and
勘違い　それも別に悪くないから
the misunderstanding, that's not too bad either
ねぇ　溶けきれない本音は　溜まって
Hey, the feelings that won't fully melt accumulate
欲しくて
and I want them
消える前に現れるの
They appear before they vanish
単調な日々の予定　吐き捨て　呆気なく
Spitting out the plans of monotonous days, so suddenly
台無しに崩れだす
It starts to crumble into a mess
ゆっくり　止まった　先に映り合うほど
Slowly, as if reflecting each other at the end of the halt
綺麗に　光りそうな　期待があった
There was an expectation that would shine beautifully
ただ　終わらない夢の中　笑ってなんていられない
In a dream that just won't end, I can't just keep smiling
目を開け　突き確かめていた　痛いって歌う
Open your eyes, I was confirming it, singing that it hurts
今　人から借りてきた　言葉あてに進まないで
Now, don't move forward relying on words borrowed from others
胸響かせないで
Don't let them resonate in your heart
結局は自分次第に
In the end, it's up to you
...寄り添って行こう
...let's go side by side.
世界は一つでもないし
The world isn't just one thing,
結局は自分次第に
and in the end, it's all up to you.
はい！
Yes!
おお～
Whoa~
ということで、あやあや、楽しかったね、あやあや！
So, Aya-aya, that was fun, Aya-aya!
そうそう、そうだね。
Yes, yes, it was.
最高だったね、あやあや！
It was the best, Aya-aya!
そう、ヤバい、私たち...
Yeah, it's crazy how we...
息ぴったりだったじゃん！
...were perfectly in sync!
そうだよね！もう、こんなのやっちゃってね、こんな。
Right! I mean, we were doing all this, like this.
あやあや、ヤバい。あははは。
Aya-aya, this is crazy. Ahahaha.
ということで、今日はかなたちゃんに...
So, today, for Kanata-chan...
あ、あ、すいません。すいません。
Oh, oh, excuse me. Excuse me.
今日、かなたちゃんに来ていただきました！ありがとうございます！
We have Kanata-chan here today! Thank you so much!
ありがとうございます！天音かなたです。
Thank you! I'm Amane Kanata.
よろしくお願いします。
Nice to meet you.
よろしくお願いします。歌い終わったんですけど。
Nice to meet you. We just finished singing.
終わりましたね。
We did.
今日ね、あの、歌ってもらった「clever」って曲なんですけど。
So about the song we sang today, 'clever'...
はい、余が大好きなClariSさんの曲なんですけど。
Yes, it's a song by ClariS, whom I love.
おお、すごい素敵なんだよね。
Oh, it's a really wonderful song.
でも、かなたもさ、ClariS好きじゃん、たぶん。
But you like ClariS too, don't you, Kanata?
好き好き！
I love them!
好きなんだろうなっていうのを思ってて。
I figured you would.
なんか、そう、伝わってると。
I guess it showed.
そう、思ってて。で、しかも「clever」って曲、ちょっとかっこいいじゃん。
Yeah, I thought so. And 'clever' is a pretty cool song.
そう。
True.
で、なんかよくかっこいい歌を一緒にかなたちゃんと歌いたいなって思ってて。
And I've always wanted to sing a cool song with you, Kanata.
で、「clever」を聴いたときに、「これかなたちゃんしかいない」と思ったの。
When I heard 'clever', I thought, 'It has to be Kanata-chan.'
ヤバいヤバいヤバい。
Oh wow, oh wow, oh wow.
で、かなたちゃんに一緒に歌ってくれませんかっていうのを送ったんですけど。
So I sent a message asking if you'd sing it with me.
いや、もう本当に大喜び。
I was absolutely overjoyed.
本当に？
Really?
喜びすぎて、急に心の距離縮めちゃって、あやあや。
I was so happy, I suddenly felt much closer to you, Aya-aya.
距離縮めてもらいました。頑張って返していきたいと思います。
You definitely did. I'll try my best to match that energy.
今日はね。
Today, though...
本当に嬉しい。あやめ先輩のね、歌も声も大好きっていうのは、
I'm so happy. I've always loved your singing and your voice, Ayame-senpai.
本当にデビューする前に、ホロメンのみんなに挨拶回りに行ったときにも、余にちょっと送れたんだよね。
Even before my debut, when I was greeting all the Holo-members, I sent you a message.
すごい持ち上げてくれてね。
You were so complimentary.
持ち上げてない、本当、事実事実。事実を陳列罪したんですよ。
I wasn't! It was just the truth. I was guilty of presenting the facts.
そしたらね、それからの、本当に一緒に歌えてとっても嬉しかったです。
So after all that, I was so happy to finally sing with you.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you so much.
ありがとうございます、こちらこそ。これからも歌ってみたとか...
Thank you, same here. Maybe we can do a 'tried singing' cover together...
良いんですか！？
Really?!
嬉しい。
I'm so glad.
はい、もちろんです。
Yes, of course.
あ、本当に今度。
Oh, definitely soon.
なんか、イベントがちょっとあったりするのかな？みたいなの、
There might be some events coming up, maybe...
ちょっと一緒に、なんかすーるかも？みたいなのもありますんで。
...we might be doing something together? There's that possibility too.
お楽しみにくださいませ。
Please look forward to it.
ということで、かなたちゃんでした！
So, that was Kanata-chan!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
ありがとね。
Thanks for coming.
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!
退屈な窓辺に　吹き込む風に
On the wind blowing through the boring window,
顔をしかめたのは　照れくささの裏返し
the reason I frowned was to hide my embarrassment.
曖昧に頷く　手のひらの今日
Nodding vaguely at today in the palm of my hand,
描いてる自分は　少し大げさで
the self I envision is a bit exaggerated.
何か変わりそうな　気がしているよ
I have a feeling that something is about to change.
心に呼びかける　君のせいだね
It's because of you, calling out to my heart.
曇り空　のぞいた光
Light peeking through the cloudy sky,
手を伸ばそう　いつよりも力強い勇気で
I'll reach out with courage stronger than ever before.
光も影も　まだ遠くて　それでも僕らは
Light and shadow are still far away, but still, we...
優しさの理由が知りたい
...want to know the reason for kindness.
今は誰の名前でもない　輝きの彼方へ
To the radiance beyond, which belongs to no one yet,
全部過去になる前に　見つけに行こう
let's go find it before it all becomes the past.
君はまるで 頼りない夢と
You are like an unreliable dream
嘯く僕の目を からかうように
Mocking my bragging eyes
君が見てる空は 何色だろう
What color is the sky you're looking at?
きっと青く高く 清らかなはず
It must be blue, high, and pure
すれ違い 近付きながら
Passing each other while getting closer
いつの日か 戸惑いも受け止めていけたら
If one day I can accept even the confusion
言葉のままじゃ もどかしくて
Words alone are frustrating
だから何度でも 不器用に重ねてしまうね
So I clumsily layer them over and over again
喜びも悲しみも ここで意味が生まれること
Joy and sadness, both finding meaning here
二人 気付き始めてる その理由を
The two of us are starting to realize the reason for it
言葉のままじゃ もどかしくて
Words alone are frustrating
何度でも
Over and over
不器用に重ねてしまうよ
I'll layer them clumsily
声にならない切なさごと
Along with the wordless sorrow
この思い 君に届け
May these feelings reach you
光も影も まだ遠くて
Both light and shadow are still far away
それでも僕らは 優しさの理由が知りたい
But even so, we want to know the reason for kindness
今は誰の名前でもない
Now to the far side of the radiance
輝きの彼方へ
That belongs to no one
全部 過去になる前に 見つけに行こう
Let's go find it before it all becomes the past
君が 過去になる前に 見つけるから
Because I'll find you before you become the past
はい！ということでね、たくさんあの、もうぶっ通しで歌って踊ったわけですけれども、皆さん楽しんでいただけてますでしょうかー！
Yes! So, I've been singing and dancing non-stop, but are you all enjoying yourselves?
今回はね、前回と違って、少しだけダンスも成長したんじゃないかなーってちょっと思うんですけど、
This time, unlike last time, I think my dancing has improved a little bit.
前回もねなんか成長したなーって思ったんだけど、今回もちょっと成長したかなーっていう風に思ってるんだけど、どうですか皆さん？
I thought I'd improved last time too, but I think I've improved a bit more this time as well. What do you all think?
うんうんうん。うんうんうん！みんな褒めてくれてる！たぶん！たぶん褒めてくれてるはずです！
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah! Everyone's praising me! Probably! I'm sure they are!
ということで、あの、なんかステージ立つんも、少し、なんか前まではね、もうなんか恥ずかしくて、もうなんかあの全然思うように動けなかったんですけど、
So, standing on stage is also... well, until before I was just embarrassed and couldn't move the way I wanted to at all.
なんか自信がね少しだけついてきて、ダンスを踊るなんか回数も多くなってきたから、ちょっとね自信がついたんですけどれも、
But I've gained a little bit of confidence, and since I've been dancing more often, I've gained a bit of confidence.
まあねそんな成長した姿をみんなに少しでも、まあ見せられたらいいかなーって思ってます！
Well, I hope I was able to show everyone at least a little bit of my growth!
ということで！嬉しいお知らせをここで二つ挟んでいきたいと思いまーす！
And with that! I'd like to share two pieces of happy news here!
二つ！二つ！
Two! Two!
じゃあまずね、一つ目から発表いきたいと思いますよー！
Well then, I'll start with the first announcement!
じゃあ行きますよー！いいですか心の準備は！
Here we go! Are you ready!
じゃかじゃかじゃかじゃかじゃか... 百鬼あやめ 誕生日記念グッズ、発売しまーす！やったー！
Drumroll... Nakiri Ayame Birthday Memorial Goods are now on sale! Yay!
百鬼あやめ 誕生記念2021
Nakiri Ayame Birthday Celebration 2021
今年もやってまいりましたよ！
It's that time of year again!
気になるね、誕生日のフルセットは、こちらです！どどん！
The birthday full set you're curious about is this! Ta-da!
あ、ちょっとすいませんね。はい。あ、逆ですねすいません。あははは。
Oh, excuse me. Yes. Oh, it's the other way around, sorry. Hahaha.
はい！えー、一つ目は、ブランケット！そしてそして、おっぱいマウスパッド！
Yes! First is a blanket! And then, an Oppai mouse pad!
おー！そして、記念ボイス！そしてそして、特典ポストカードになっております！やったー！
Oh! And a memorial voice! And finally, a special bonus postcard! Yay!
すごーい！もう盛りだくさんですよ今回も！
Amazing! It's packed with goodies this time too!
今回の記念ボイスはですね、誕生日記念、水族館デートボイスとなっておりまーす！
This time's memorial voice is a birthday celebration aquarium date voice!
余がね、水族館好きなので、ちょっとボイス、張り切って、張り切って頑張っちゃいましたよー！
Since I like aquariums, I really put my heart into this voice!
あ、ですね、ボイスはもちろん、あの単品でも購入可能ですので、はい、ボイスだけ欲しいなーって方はね、ぜひあの水族館デートを楽しんでいただいて、もろうて、
Oh, and of course, the voice can be purchased separately, so if you just want the voice, please enjoy the aquarium date.
そしてそして、特典ポストカードは、毎度お馴染みの、数量限定...
And then, the bonus postcard is the usual limited edition...
フルセット購入特典
Full Set Purchase Bonus
せーの！
Ready, set...
余の直筆サインが入ってきます！
My handwritten signature will be included!
やったー！
Yay!
なんか、小耳に挟んだんですけど...
I heard a little rumor...
前回めちゃくちゃ爆速で売れましたよっていうマネちゃん情報があったんですけど...
My manager told me that last time they sold out super fast...
今回はね、どうなることやらって感じですけど...
I wonder how it'll go this time...
このポストカードは、わさび先生の描き下ろしとなっております。
This postcard features a new illustration by Wasabi-sensei.
ありがとうございます！めちゃめちゃ可愛よー。
Thank you! It's so incredibly cute.
そして、もちろんこちらグッズ単体も購入可能ですので...
And of course, these items are also available for individual purchase...
ぜひ皆さんご検討してくださーい。
So please consider it, everyone.
「もう余のボイスはいらないです」って方ね、はい。
For those who say, "I don't need your voice anymore."
ちょっと悲しいですけど... グッズだけでもぜひ手に取っていただけたらなと思います。
It's a bit sad, but I'd be happy if you'd at least get the goods.
ブランケット
Blanket
ブランケットもわさび先生の描き下ろしなので、ぜひ手に取ってください。
The blanket is also illustrated by Wasabi-sensei, so please get one.
このブランケットも、余が「ちょっと柔らかい素材にして」って言って...
I asked for this blanket to be made of a soft material...
「固い素材は嫌だ。嫌です！」って言ってね。
Saying, "I don't like stiff materials. I refuse!"
ふわふわな生地になっておりますので...
So it's made of a fluffy fabric...
ぜひ皆さんブランケットかけて、暖かくしてください。
So please use the blanket and keep yourselves warm.
おっぱいマウスパッド
Breast Mousepad
おっぱいマウスパッドはいかもち先生の描き下ろしとなっております。ありがとうございます！
The breast mousepad is illustrated by Ikamochi-sensei. Thank you!
めちゃ可愛よ。いつもよりセクシーな感じの余ですけども、ぜひおうちに置いてください。
It's so cute. It's a sexier me than usual, so please display it in your home.
ということで、もう一つのお知らせをここで終了なんですけれども...
So, that wraps up this announcement...
ま、気になる、あとは一個ですね...
Well, there's one more thing you're probably curious about...
え？何でしょう？
Eh? What could it be?
前回は？前回の周年記念では、最後に何を発表しましたか？
Last time? At the last anniversary, what did I announce at the very end?
そうです！オリジナルソングを発表させていただきましたね。
That's right! I announced an original song.
前回は！今回も！
Last time! And this time too!
オリジナルソングが、あります！！
I have an original song!!
やったー！よいしょー！！
Yay! Alright!!
ということで、今回もオリジナル曲、用意しております。
So, I've prepared an original song this time as well.
ずっと準備して、歌も踊りもめちゃくちゃ練習してきたので...
I've been preparing and practicing the song and dance a lot...
ぜひ見てください！
So please watch!
じゃあちょっと、余、お色直ししてきますので...
Well then, I'm going to go change my outfit...
みなさん、ちょっと待っててね！バイバーイ！
Everyone, please wait a little bit! Bye-bye!
夢花火
作詞：HaTo 作曲：HaTo
Dream Fireworks
Lyrics: HaTo Composition: HaTo
鈴の音響く 深い夜とお月様
The sound of bells echoing, the deep night and the moon
今宵宴だ宵祝
Tonight is a feast, a festive celebration
歌い舞え 昂れ 式神を連れ立って
Sing and dance, be uplifted, bringing the Shikigami along
戯れに興じるの
Let's indulge in the frolic
流れゆく時を想う
Thinking of the flowing time
消えゆく日ならば
If it's a day that fades away
この刹那さえ美しくしよう
Let's make even this moment beautiful
咲かせて 空高く
Let it bloom, high in the sky
そっと はんなりはんなり 夢花火
Softly, elegantly, elegantly, dream fireworks
ふんわりふんわり 願うのは
Gently, gently, what I wish for
現世の思い出だけ ずっと
Only the memories of this fleeting world, forever
ずっと 幾星霜を重ねて
Forever, through many years and seasons
巡り合う縁は情け
The bonds we meet are a blessing
とこしえに余は 歌って笑っていたいのだ
Eternally, I want to keep singing and laughing
静けさ満ちる 浮かび出づる影法師
Filled with silence, a silhouette emerges
今宵祭りの後よ
Tonight, after the festival
寂しさ抑え ああ 水面を想いながら
Suppressing the loneliness, ah, while thinking of the water's surface
微睡みへ委ねるの
I surrender myself to a slumber
生まれては弾け消える
Born only to burst and vanish
うたかたの調べは
The transient melody is...
その一瞬も大切にしよう
Let's cherish that very moment too
満たして 鮮やかに
Fill it, vividly
そっと きんらりきんらり 夢花火
Softly, glitteringly, glitteringly, dream fireworks
ひっそりひっそり 祈るのは
Quietly, quietly, what I pray for
永遠の楽しさだけ ずっと
Only eternal joy, forever
ずっと 幾星霜を重ねて
Forever, through many years and seasons
思い出す縁はあはれ
The bonds I remember are so moving
心ゆくまで 踊って騒いでいたいのだ
Until my heart's content, I want to keep dancing and carousing
夢花火
Dream Fireworks
移り行く時の中で
In the midst of passing time
宿る火もさらば
Farewell to the dwelling fire
この現世も彩りとなれ
Let even this world be colored
咲かせて 鮮やかに
Let it bloom, vividly
皆と
With everyone
そっとはらり はらり 夢花火
Softly falling, falling, dream fireworks
ふわり ふわり 祈るのは
Softly, softly, what I pray for
現世の愉しさだけ
Is only the joy of this world
いつまでも
Forever
幾歳月を重ねて
Through many years and months
巡り合う情け
The kindness we find in our encounters
忘れないように
So that I won't forget
常しえに
For eternity
皆と笑っていたいのじゃ
I want to be laughing with everyone
NAKIRI AYAME BIRTHDAY 4th Anniversary Live